Guide to the Peter E. Soderbergh Collection of Jehovah's Witnesses Materials, 1914-1995 AIS.1972.08
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Peter E. Soderbergh Collection of Jehovah's Witnesses Materials
1914-1995
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Soderbergh, Peter A.
AIS.1972.08
20 Linear Feet
This collection of books, periodicals, and pamphlets contains materials related to the Jehovah's Witnesses, a Christian sect.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
Peter E. Soderbergh Collection of Jehovah's Witnesses Materials, AIS.1972.08, 1914-1995, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into four series:
Series I. History, 1957-1966
Series II. Works Published by the Society, 1921-1994
Series III. Programs, 1966-1985
Series IV. Critical and Controversial Works, 1914-1995
Biography
Pastor Charles Taze Russell (1852-1916) was a Pittsburgh native who worked as a clerk in his father's store when he founded the International Bible Students Association in 1880. He then co-founded the Watch Tower Bible and Tract Society in 1881. Both served as organizations to promote Russell's theology. His teachings gave rise to several splinter sects, of which the most notable is the Jehovah's Witnesses. After his wife divorced Russell, he left Pittsburgh for Brooklyn, N. Y. Throughout his ministry he travelled frequently, making trips to the Holy Land, throughout the United States, and around the world.
Dr. Peter A. Soderbergh (1928-1998) was Professor and Dean of Education at Louisiana State University; prior to that he held academic positions at the University of Pittsburgh and University of Virginia. His son, Steven Soderbergh, is a film director and producer. Dr. Soderbergh was an avid historian and Marine Corps veteran. Shortly before his death, he authored two volumes on women serving in World War II and the Korean War. His interest in the Jehovah's Witnesses sect resulted in a monograph which is included in this collection, but was never widely circulated.
The collection is dedicated to Peter E. Soderbergh, the son of Dr. Peter A. Soderbergh and brother of Steven Soderbergh, in accordance with the donor's wishes.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dr. Peter A. Soderbergh, 1972-1995.
Religious newspapers and periodicals; Religious literature; Christian sects; Jehovah's Witnesses; Churches and Synagogues; Jehovah's Witnesses -- United States -- History; Jehovah's Witnesses -- Doctrines; Russell, C. T. (Charles Taze); International Bible Students Association; Watch Tower Bible and Tract Society
- History, 1957-1966; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains three monographs relating to the history and background of the Jehovah's Witnesses and its founder, Pastor Charles Taze Russell.
  - Jehovah's first witness: Pastor Charles Taze Russell, by Peter A. Soderbergh, 1966 (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Faith on the March, circa 1957 (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Jehovah's Witnesses in the divine purpose, circa 1959 (Box 1, Item 3)
  - Sample Correspondence, Leadership, and Locations (Box 1, Item 4)
- Works Published By the Society, 1921-1994; II.
  This series contains works published by the Watchtower Bible and Tract Society, the leading Jehovah's Witnesses organization, founded by Charles Taze Russell. These works are divided into the following four subseries: Monographs, Reference, Periodicals, Index. The Monographs subseries contains work published by the International Bible Students Association and Watch Tower Society including Bible Translations, and treatises on Jehovah's Witnesses beliefs. The Reference subseries contains Yearbooks of Jehovah's Witnesses spanning from 1930-1994 and a report commissioned by the Assembly of Jehovah's Witnesses around the World. The Periodicals subseries contains the Watch Tower Bible and Tract Society Publications Awake! and The Watch Tower. The Index subseries contains Watch Tower Society publication indices for the years 1930-1985.
  - Monographs, 1.
    - New World Translation of the Hebrew Scriptures, Vol. 1, 1953 (Box 1, Item 5)
    - New World Translation of the Hebrew Scriptures, Vol. 2, 1955 (Box 1, Item 6)
    - New World Translation of the Holy Scriptures, 1961 (Box 1, Item 7)
    - Diaglott Bible (Box 1, Item 8)
    - Millenial Dawn: The Divine Plan of the Ages, Volume 1, 1902 (Box 1, Item 9)
    - Millenial Dawn: Thy Kingdom Come, Volume 3, 1904 (Box 2, Item 10)
    - Studies in the Scriptures: The Divine Plan of the Ages, Ser. 1, 1914 (Box 2, Item 11)
    - Studies in the Scriptures: The Time is at Hand, Ser. 2, 1923 (Box 2, Item 12)
    - Studies in the Scriptures: The Battle of Armageddon, Ser. 4, 1923 (Box 2, Item 13)
    - Studies in the Scriptures: The Atonement Between God and Man, Ser. 5 (Box 2, Item 14)
    - Studies in the Scriptures: The New Creation, Ser. 6, 1914 (Box 2, Item 15)
    - Children: Their Training and Their Hope, 1941 (Box 2, Item 16)
    - Creation, 1927 (Box 2, Item 17)
    - Deliverance!, 1926 (Box 3, Item 18)
    - Enemies, 1937 (Box 3, Item 19)
    - Government, 1928 (Box 3, Item 20)
    - The Harp of God, 1921 (Box 3, Item 21)
    - Jehovah, 1934 (Box 3, Item 22)
    - The Kingdom: Hope of the World, 1931 (Box 3, Item 23)
    - The Last Days, 1928 (Box 3, Item 24)
    - Life, 1929 (Box 3, Item 25)
    - Light, Book One, 1930 (Box 3, Item 26)
    - Light, Book Two, 1930 (Box 3, Item 27)
    - The New World, 1942 (Box 3, Item 28)
    - Preparation, 1933 (Box 3, Item 29)
    - Preservation, 1932 (Box 4, Item 30)
    - Prophecy, 1929 (Box 4, Item 31)
    - Reconciliation, 1928 (Box 4, Item 32)
    - Religion, 1940 (Box 4, Item 33)
    - Riches, 1936 (Box 4, Item 34)
    - Salvation, 1939 (Box 4, Item 35)
    - Vindication, 1931 (Box 4, Item 36)
    - Warning: Two Bible Treatises, 1938 (Box 4, Item 37)
    - Defending and Legally Establishing the Good News, 1950 (Box 4, Item 38)
    - "Equipped for Every Good Work", 1946 (Box 4, Item 39)
    - "Let God Be True", 1946 (Box 4, Item 40)
    - "New Heavens and New Earth", 1953 (Box 4, Item 41)
    - Qualified to be Ministers, 1967 (Box 4, Item 42)
    - Truth: Shall It Be Supressed Or WIll Congress Protect the People's Rights?, 1934 (Box 4, Item 43)
    - What Has Religion Done for Mankind, 1951 (Box 5, Item 44)
    - You may Survive Armageddon into God's New World, 1955 (Box 5, Item 45)
    - Aid to Bible Understanding, 1971 (Box 5, Item 46)
    - "All Scripture is Inspried of God and Beneficial", 1963 (Box 5, Item 47)
    - "Babylon the Great has Fallen!": God's Kingdom Rules!, 1963 (Box 5, Item 48)
    - From Paradise Lost to Paradise Regained, 1958 (Box 5, Item 49)
    - Is the Bible really the World of God?, 1969 (Box 5, Item 50)
    - Did Man Get Here By Evolution or By Creation?, 1967 (Box 5, Item 51)
    - "Let Your Name Be Sanctified", 1961 (Box 5, Item 52)
    - Life Everlasting in Freedom of the Sons of God, 1966 (Box 5, Item 53)
    - Listen To The Great Teacher, 1971 (Box 5, Item 54)
    - "Make Sure Of All Things Hold Fast To What Is Fine", 1965 (Box 6, Item 55)
    - "The Nations Shall Know That I Am Jehovah" - How?, 1971 (Box 6, Item 56)
    - Paradise Restored to Mankind - By Theocracy!, 1972 (Box 6, Item 57)
    - "Then Is Finished The Mystery of God", 1969 (Box 6, Item 58)
    - "Things In Which It Is Impossible For God To Lie", 1965 (Box 6, Item 59)
    - The Truth that leads to Eternal Life, 1968 (Box 6, Item 60)
    - When God Speaks Peace to all Nations, 1959 (Box 6, Item 61)
    - "Your Will Be Done On Earth", 1958 (Box 6, Item 62)
    - "Your Word Is a Lamp to My Foot", 1967 (Box 6, Item 63)
  - Reference, 2.
    - "Report on Everlasting Good News", 1963 June - September (Box 6, Item 64)
    - 1930 Yearbook of the I.B.S.A., 1929 (Box 6, Item 65)
    - 1931 Yearbook of the I.B.S.A., 1930 (Box 6, Item 66)
    - 1943 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1942 (Box 6, Item 67)
    - 1945 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1944 (Box 6, Item 68)
    - 1947 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1946 (Box 7, Item 69)
    - 1949 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1948 (Box 7, Item 70)
    - 1953 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1952 (Box 7, Item 71)
    - 1956 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1955 (Box 7, Item 72)
    - 1958 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1957 (Box 7, Item 73)
    - 1959 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1958 (Box 7, Item 74)
    - 1960 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1959 (Box 7, Item 75)
    - 1961 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1960 (Box 7, Item 76)
    - 1962 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1961 (Box 7, Item 77)
    - 1963 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1962 (Box 7, Item 78)
    - 1964 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1963 (Box 7, Item 79)
    - 1965 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1964 (Box 7, Item 80)
    - 1966 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1965 (Box 8, Item 81)
    - 1967 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses (Box 8, Item 82)
    - 1968 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1967 (Box 8, Item 83)
    - 1969 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses (Box 8, Item 84)
    - 1970 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1969 (Box 8, Item 85)
    - 1971 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1970 (Box 8, Item 86)
    - 1972 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1971 (Box 8, Item 87)
    - 1973 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1972 (Box 8, Item 88)
    - 1974 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1973 (Box 8, Item 89)
    - 1975 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1974 (Box 8, Item 89)
    - 1976 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1975 (Box 8, Item 90)
    - 1977 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1976 (Box 8, Item 91)
    - 1978 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1977 (Box 9, Item 92)
    - 1979 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1978 (Box 9, Item 93)
    - 1980 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1979 (Box 9, Item 94)
    - 1981 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1980 (Box 9, Item 95)
    - 1982 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1981 (Box 9, Item 96)
    - 1983 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1982 (Box 9, Item 97)
    - 1984 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1983 (Box 9, Item 98)
    - 1985 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1984 (Box 9, Item 99)
    - 1986 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1985 (Box 9, Images 100)
    - 1987 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1986 (Box 9, Item 101)
    - 1988 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1987 (Box 9, Item 102)
    - 1989 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1988 (Box 9, Item 103)
    - 1990 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1989 (Box 9, Item 104)
    - 1992 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1991 (Box 9, Item 105)
    - 1994 Yearbook of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1993 (Box 9a, Item 106)
  - Periodicals, 3.
    - Awake!, Volume 53, 1972 (Box 9a, Item 107)
    - Awake!, "Child Abuse - Why?", 1976 July 22 (Box 9a, Item 108)
    - Awake!, "Will There Be Enough Food To Eat?", 1980 August 22 (Box 9a, Item 109)
    - Awake!, "Armageddon: Nuclear Holocaust or A New Start?", 1983 December 22 (Box 9a, Item 110)
    - Awake!, "Nazism: Could It Happen Again?", 1985 June 8 (Box 9a, Item 111)
    - The Watchtower, 1966 (Box 9a, Item 112)
    - The Watchtower, "'Go..Make Disciples...Baptizing Them'"..., 1969 December 15 (Box 9a, Item 113)
    - The Watchtower, "'They Followed Him'"..., 1967 January 1 (Box 9a, Item 114)
    - The Watchtower, "Making Grateul Use of A 'Penny'"..., 1967 January 15 (Box 9a, Item 115)
    - The Watchtower, "Jehovah Makes Full Might Abound"..., 1967 February 15 (Box 9a, Item 116)
    - The Watchtower, "A God Of Loving-Kindness"..., 1967 March 1 (Box 9a, Item 117)
    - The Watchtower, "Learn By Contrast To Appreciate True Riches"..., 1967 March 15 (Box 9a, Item 118)
    - The Watchtower, "The Pattern of Judgment"..., 1967 April 1 (Box 9a, Item 119)
    - The Watchtower, "Mankind's Millennium Under God's Kingdom"..., 1967 April 15 (Box 9a, Item 120)
    - The Watchtower, "Remember Your Creator By Manifesting Goodness"..., 1967 May 1 (Box 9a, Item 121)
    - The Watchtower, "Mildness, A Christian Requirement"..., 1967 May 15 (Box 9a, Item 122)
    - The Watchtower, "God Kindly Leads His People Toward Life"..., 1967 June 1 (Box 9a, Item 123)
    - The Watchtower, "Faith Required to Please God"..., 1967 June 15 (Box 9a, Item 124)
    - The Watchtower, "Developing and Displaying Self-Control"..., 1967 July 1 (Box 9a, Item 125)
    - The Watchtower, "Festivals of Praise To Jehovah"..., 1967 July 15 (Box 9a, Item 126)
    - The Watchtower, "Keeping Free From The Spirit Of Complaint"..., 1967 August 1 (Box 9a, Item 127)
    - The Watchtower, "The Need For Security"..., 1967 August 15 (Box 9a, Item 128)
    - The Watchtower, "Keeping The Tongue Under Control"..., 1967 September 1 (Box 9a, Item 130)
    - The Watchtower, "God's Spirit And Word - Divine Provisions For Life"..., 1967 September 15 (Box 9a, Item 131)
    - The Watchtower, "Finding Freedom With Jehovah's Visible Organization"..., 1967 October 1 (Box 9a, Item 132)
    - The Watchtower, "Rescuing A Great Crowd of Mankind Out of Armageddon"..., 1967 October 15 (Box 9a, Item 133)
    - The Watchtower, "'Let God Arise, Let His Enemies Be Scattered'"..., 1967 November 1 (Box 9a, Item 134)
    - The Watchtower, "'Let Down Your Nets For A Catch'"..., 1967 November 15 (Box 9a, Item 135)
    - The Watchtower, "Saving The World of Mankind By Blood"..., 1967 December 1 (Box 9a, Item 136)
    - The Watchtower, "'In All Nations The Good News Has To Be Preached First'"..., 1967 December 15 (Box 9a, Item 137)
    - The Watchtower, "'Your Deliverance is Getting Near'"..., 1968 December 15 (Box 9a, Item 138)
    - The Watchtower, "Watch Yourself And Your Teaching"..., 1968 December 1 (Box 9a, Item 139)
    - The Watchtower, "The Happiness of The 'Nation Whose God Is Jehovah'"..., 1968 November 15 (Box 9a, Item 140)
    - The Watchtower, "The 'Good News' Of A World Without False Religion"..., 1968 November 1 (Box 9a, Item 141)
    - The Watchtower, "Man's Rule About To Give Way To God's Rule"..., 1968 October 15 (Box 9a, Item 142)
    - The Watchtower, "Maintain Proper Christian Balance"..., 1968 October 1 (Box 9a, Item 143)
    - The Watchtower, "'This Is The Land Of The Word Of Truth"..., 1968 September 15 (Box 9a, Item 144)
    - The Watchtower, "'Whatever A Man Is Sowing This He Will Also Reap'"..., 1968 September 1 (Box 9a, Item 145)
    - The Watchtower, "The Book Of Truthful Historical Dates"..., 1968 August 15 (Box 9a, Item 146)
    - The Watchtower, "Become Zealous For Jehovah"..., 1968 August 1 (Box 9a, Item 147)
    - The Watchtower, "The Holy Scriptures Supply Spiritual Needs"..., 1968 July 15 (Box 9a, Item 148)
    - The Watchtower, "Empowering A Priesthood For Effectual Service"..., 1968 July 1 (Box 9a, Item 149)
    - The Watchtower, "A Heavenly Preisthood - God's Provision For Life Seekers"..., 1968 June 15 (Box 9a, Item 150)
    - The Watchtower, "Seeking The Way Of Approach To The Source Of Life"..., 1968 June 1 (Box 9a, Item 151)
    - The Watchtower, "Recognizing God's Requirements For Life"..., 1968 May 15 (Box 9a, Item 152)
    - The Watchtower, "Understanding Time A Help To True Worshipers"..., 1968 May 1 (Box 9a, Item 153)
    - The Watchtower, "What God's High Priest Will Do For The People"..., 1968 April 15 (Box 9a, Item 154)
    - The Watchtower, "God's Word Keeps Your Faith Alive"..., 1968 April 1 (Box 9a, Item 155)
    - The Watchtower, "True Worship Under Challenge"..., 1968 March 15 (Box 9a, Item 156)
    - The Watchtower, "Rejoicing In The God Of True Worship"..., 1968 March 1 (Box 9a, Item 157)
    - The Watchtower, "Husbands, Assume Your Responsibilities of Headship"..., 1968 February 15 (Box 9a, Item 158)
    - The Watchtower, "Parents' Moral Responsibility"... (Box 9a, Item 159)
    - The Watchtower, "The Righteous Standard Of The Changeless God"..., 1968 January 15 (Box 9a, Item 160)
    - The Watchtower, "How Great A Witness?"..., 1968 January 1 (Box 9a, Item 161)
    - The Watchtower, "Fruitful Christians Manifest Godly Contentment"..., 1967 February 1 (Box 9a, Item 162)
    - The Watchtower, "Final Woes to Enemies of Peace with God"..., 1969 December 1 (Box 9a, Item 163)
    - The Watchtower, "The Writing of Correct Words of Truth"..., 1969 November 15 (Box 9a, Item 164)
    - The Watchtower, "Acquaint Yourself With God and Keep Peace"..., 1969 November 1 (Box 9a, Item 165)
    - The Watchtower, "The Approaching Peace of A Thousand Years"..., 1969 October 15 (Box 9a, Item 166)
    - The Watchtower, "Pay Attention to the 'Prophetic Word'"..., 1969 October 1 (Box 9a, Item 168)
    - The Watchtower, "Return Evil For Evil to No One"..., 1969 September 15 (Box 9a, Item 169)
    - The Watchtower, "Jehovah, The Great Overseer and Shepherd of His People"..., 1969 July 1 (Box 9a, Item 170)
    - The Watchtower, "Joyful Endurer or Unhappy Dropout - Which?"..., 1969 July 15 (Box 9a, Item 171)
    - The Watchtower, "Make Your Advancement Manifest By Responding To God's Word"..., 1969 April 1 (Box 9a, Item 172)
    - The Watchtower, "What Influences Decisions In Your Life"..., 1969 March 15 (Box 9a, Item 173)
    - The Watchtower, "Laying A Foundation For the Right Kind of Ministers"..., 1969 March 1 (Box 9a, Item 174)
    - The Watchtower, "Look To The Bible As Our Guide In Life"..., 1969 February 15 (Box 9a, Item 175)
    - The Watchtower, "Appreciating Jehovah"..., 1969 February 1 (Box 9a, Item 176)
    - The Watchtower, "The Faith That Pleases God"..., 1969 January 15 (Box 9a, Item 177)
    - The Watchtower, "'You Must Not Forget'"..., 1969 January 1 (Box 9a, Item 178)
    - The Watchtower, "The Desolating of Christendom By The 'Disgusting Thing'"..., 1970 December 1 (Box 9a, Item 179)
    - The Watchtower, "End Of Worldwide Witnessing Gets Near"..., 1970 December 15 (Box 9a, Item 180)
    - The Watchtower, "'We Worship What We Know'"..., 1970 November 15 (Box 9a, Item 181)
    - The Watchtower, "Taking Final Advantage Of The 'Year Of Goodwill'"..., 1970 November 1 (Box 9a, Item 182)
    - The Watchtower, "Saving The Human Race In The Kingdom Way"..., 1970 October 15 (Box 9a, Item 183)
    - The Watchtower, "Breaking The Yoke Of The Oppressor"..., 1970 October 1 (Box 9a, Item 184)
    - The Watchtower, "The Blessings Of Obedience Learned Through Suffering"..., 1970 September 15 (Box 9a, Item 185)
    - The Watchtower, "Jehovah's Servants Are Different"..., 1970 August 15 (Box 9a, Item 186)
    - The Watchtower, "Jehovah's Name To Be Declared In All The Earth"..., 1970 August 1 (Box 9a, Item 187)
    - The Watchtower, "Meeting The Divine Requirement of Obedience"..., 1970 July 15 (Box 9a, Item 188)
    - The Watchtower, "Personally Benefiting From The Bible's Laws And Principles"..., 1970 July 1 (Box 9a, Item 189)
    - The Watchtower, "The Righteous Law Of The King Eternal Is The Truth"..., 1970 June 15 (Box 9a, Item 190)
    - The Watchtower, "Do You Have 'Faith To The Preserving Alive of The Soul'"..., 1970 June 1 (Box 9a, Item 191)
    - The Watchtower, "Baptism Of Those Who Are Disciples"..., 1970 May 15 (Box 9a, Item 192)
    - The Watchtower, "Keep Close In Mind 'The Conclusion Of The System Of Things'"..., 1970 May 1 (Box 9a, Item 193)
    - The Watchtower, "The Road Back To Peace In Paradise"..., 1970 April 15 (Box 9a, Item 194)
    - The Watchtower, "Building Disciples Having The Quality Of Endurance"..., 1970 April 1 (Box 9a, Item 195)
    - The Watchtower, "Heavenly Support Of Kingdom Preaching"..., 1970 March 15 (Box 9a, Item 196)
    - The Watchtower, "What Is The Future Of Today's Youth?"..., 1970 March 1 (Box 9a, Item 197)
    - The Watchtower, "'With All That You Acquire, Acquire Understanding'"..., 1970 February 15 (Box 9a, Item 198)
    - The Watchtower, "Loyal Advocates Of The Word Of God"..., 1970 February 1 (Box 9a, Item 199)
    - The Watchtower, "The Coming 'Great Tribulation' Foreshadowed"..., 1970 January 15 (Box 9a, Item 200)
    - The Watchtower, "The Implanting Of The Word"..., 1970 January 1 (Box 9a, Item 201)
    - The Watchtower, "Have You Entered The Great Contest Of Faith"..., 1971 January 1 (Box 9a, Item 202)
    - The Watchtower, "Do You Believe In Evolution Or Creation?"..., 1971 January 15 (Box 9a, Item 203)
    - The Watchtower, "The Good News That Unites Mankind"..., 1971 May 15 (Box 9a, Item 204)
    - The Watchtower, "Appreciating Jehovah God And Jesus Christ"..., 1971 May 1 (Box 9a, Item 205)
    - The Watchtower, "'Restoration Of All Things Of Which God Spoke"..., 1971 April 15 (Box 9a, Item 206)
    - The Watchtower, "Uniting The Divided Household"..., 1971 April 1 (Box 9a, Item 207)
    - The Watchtower, "Persecution By Permission Of Jehovah - Why?"..., 1971 March 15 (Box 9a, Item 208)
    - The Watchtower, "How Is Your Heart?"..., 1971 March 1 (Box 9a, Item 209)
    - The Watchtower, "Are You Waiting For 'The Call'"..., 1971 June 1 (Box 9a, Item 210)
    - The Watchtower, "Remembering Your Creator In The Days Of Your Young Manhood"..., 1971 June 15 (Box 9a, Item 211)
    - The Watchtower, "Come Before Jehovah With Thanksgiving"..., 1971 July 1 (Box 9a, Item 212)
    - The Watchtower, "Deliverance From The Authority Of Darkness"..., 1971 July 15 (Box 9a, Item 213)
    - The Watchtower, "Having The Truth That Leads To Eternal Life"..., 1971 August 1 (Box 9a, Item 214)
    - The Watchtower, "Why Has Good Allowed The Righteous To Suffer"..., 1971 August 15 (Box 9a, Item 215)
    - The Watchtower, "Fortify Yourself So As To Maintain Integrity"..., 1971 September 1 (Box 9a, Item 216)
    - The Watchtower, "Set Apart From The World"..., 1971 September 15 (Box 9a, Item 217)
    - The Watchtower, "Is My Home Wholesome?"..., 1971 October 1 (Box 9a, Item 218)
    - The Watchtower, "When All Nations Collide, Head On, With God"..., 1971 October 15 (Box 9a, Item 219)
    - The Watchtower, "Whose Name Do Your Respect More - Your Own Or God's"..., 1971 November 1 (Box 9a, Item 220)
    - The Watchtower, "Theocratic Organization Amidst Democracies And Communism"..., 1971 November 15 (Box 9a, Item 221)
    - The Watchtower, "Bringing The Holy Place Into Right Condition"..., 1971 December 1 (Box 9a, Item 222)
    - The Watchtower, "Forward Into The New Order Under Theocracy"..., 1971 December 15 (Box 9a, Item 223)
    - The Watchtower, 1972... (Box 9a, Item 224)
    - The Watchtower, "Courage In Walking With God"..., 1980 August 15 (Box 9a, Item 225)
    - The Watchtower, "What Does Christmas Music Really Teach?"..., 1983 December 15 (Box 9a, Item 226)
    - The Watchtower, "Reflections of An Olympic Track Star"..., 1976 July 15 (Box 9a, Item 227)
    - The Watchtower, "Adam And Eve: Myth Or Reality?"..., 1985 June 1 (Box 9a, Item 228)
    - Jehovah's Witnesses in The Twentieth Century, 1978 (Box 9a, Item 229)
  - Index, 4.
    - Watch Tower Publications Index 1930-1960, 1961 (Box 11, Item 230)
    - Watch Tower Publications Index 1961-1965, 1966 (Box 11, Item 231)
    - Watch Tower Publications Index 1966, circa 1967 (Box 11, Item 232)
- Programs, 1966-1985; III.
  This series contains two event programs from Jehovah's Witnesses District Assemblies in Pittsburgh held in July 1976 and July 1972.
  - Program, District Assembly, Pittsburgh, 1967 July 27 - 30 (Box 11, Item 233)
  - Program, District Assembly, Pittsburgh, 1972 July 6 - 9 (Box 11, Item 234)
- Critical and Controversial Works, 1914-1995; IV.
  This series contains works both critical of the Jehovah's Witnesses theology and controversial to it. These include theological disputes with the teachings of the Jehovah's Witnesses, publications of the Watch Tower Bible and Tract Society intended to encourage followers of the faith to clarify dogma, a Bible translation published by the Watchtower Bible and Tract Society of New York, and an account written by a former Jehovah's Witness who became estranged from the faith and left the church.
  - Jehovah's Witnesses, 1957 (Box 11, Item 235)
  - The Theology of the Jehovah's Witnesses, 1962 (Box 11, Item 236)
  - Thirty Years a Watch Tower Slave, 1956 (Box 11, Item 237)
  - The Inside Story of Jehovah's Witnesses, 1967 (Box 11, Item 238)